User Manual

Welcome to Briefcase, the most streamlined iPhone app for getting files from one Mac to another.

Briefcase is designed to be simple and intuitive.  It is our hope that you will not need to read this user manual.  If you have any comments or questions, then please contact us at support@heymacsoftware.com.

￼
Connect 
The first step when getting started with Briefcase is to connect to a computer and download files.  This is accomplished using the “Connect” tab.

Briefcase can connect to any Mac which has “Remote Login” enabled in the System Preferences under “Sharing.”  You can access System Preferences on your Macintosh computer using the Apple menu.

The “Connect” tab will automatically discover any computers on the local network that Briefcase can connect to using Apple’s Bonjour networking technology.  You will be prompted for your username and password, with an option to save the information in the system keychain.

NOTE ABOUT PASSWORDS
If you store your passwords in the keychain, then it is strongly recommended that you enable the “Passcode Lock” on your iPhone in the Settings application under “General.”  Otherwise, anyone who has your iPhone will be able to browse the files on any machines for which you have stored passwords.  Note that other applications on the iPhone cannot see the passwords you store in Briefcase.

Briefcase can also connect to any other type of machine (eg Linux) that supports remote login via secure shell (ssh).
It is possible to connect to  remote machines over the internet by adding a bookmark to your remote server list.  Select the “Remote” tab and click on the ” (add) button.

When you add a remote server to your bookmark list, you will be asked for the following:
 Nickname - The name that will appear in your bookmark list.
 Server Address - The address of the machine either as an IP address (e.g. 192.168.1.1) or  as an internet address (e.g. family-imac.local).
 Port Number - The port number the server accepts SSH connections on. This is almost always 22.
 Username - Your username on the machine you are connecting to.

￼
Get File
The “Get File” tab allows you to browse the file system of the machine you are connected to. Tap on the directory name to browse the files in it and tap on a specific file name to download the file. The top item in any directory view will, when tapped on, download the whole directory into Briefcase.

By default, the “Get File” tab will use your home directory on the computer you are connected to as the starting point for browsing. If you need to find files that are outside your home directory, you can do so by tapping the “Options” button. This will display a segmented button that will allow you to switch from using the “Home” directory to the “Volumes” directory (root directory on a non-Mac) as your initial browsing point. When you tap the “Option” button a second time, to hide the controls, you will be taken to the browsing location you have selected. 

The “Options” controls also allow you to show hidden files.

Please note that Briefcase will grab a thumbnail image of a file when it is downloaded, though only if you are connected to a Macintosh running OS X 10.5 (Leopard) or later.

￼
Files
The Briefcase “Files” tab lets you browse the files you have downloaded. Tapping on an entry will show you information about the file, and if you are connected to a machine, will give you options for uploading or performing actions using the file (e.g. setting the desktop background on the connected Mac using an image file).

Even when you are not connected, you will still have the option to view any file types supported by MobileSafari and the built-in media viewer, including PDF, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Pages, Numbers, Keynote, MP3, M4V, text, and more.

There are a variety of operations available that are specific to particular file types and you are encouraged to explore the available options. If you have suggestions about operations you would like to see added in the future, contact feedback@heymacsoftware.com.

Deleting a file from Briefcase is as easy as swiping on the file entry and pressing the delete button that appears. Alternately you can delete a file using the “Edit” button. 

￼
Activity
The “Activity” tab displays the progress of download or upload operations. Any in-progress operation may also be cancelled here.

Operations will be halted the moment you quit Briefcase. The next time you run the software, however, it will attempt to resume unfinished uploads or downloads.

Support and Feedback
Please email support requests to support@heymacsoftware.com or send us your general feedback at feedback@heymacsoftware.com
